Finding Aid for Medical-Surgical Nursing Area (University of Michigan) records, 1960-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Medical-Surgical Nursing Area 1960-1982
  - Graduate Program 1960-1982
    - Curriculum and Program Design
      - Revisions, Proposals, and Reviews
        - Miscellaneous
          - Graduate Program in Psychiatric Nursing (Box 4)
          - Memos on Curriculum 1980-1981 (scattered) (Box 4)
          - Practicum 1981-1982 (Box 4)
          - Pre-Graduation Course Evaluation Form 1981-1982 (Box 4)
          - Research Sequence 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - Students
      The Student subseries contains a wealth of admissions and enrollment figures, information on students, and samples of student papers.
      - Admission, Enrollment, and Student Profile Data
        - 1962-1972 Students in Program--Schools Attended and Degrees Received (Box 4)
        - Enrollment Data f or Surgeon General I s Of f ice 1962-1973 (Box 4)
        - Enrollment and Admissions Statistics 1962-1974 (Box 4)
        - Enrollment and Graduation Data 1962-1975 (Box 4)
        - Information on Students 1975 (Box 4)
        - Program Inquiries (summaries) 1976-1978 (Box 4)
        - Summary Admission Data, by Term 1976-1978 (Box 4)
        - Minority Enrollment and Miscellaneous 1978-1979 (Box 4)
        - Personal Characteristics of Students Enrolled 1979-1980 (Box 4)
        - Recruitment Day 1980-1981 (Box 4)
        - Program Data 1980-1981 (Box 4)
        - Enrollment Projections 1980-1981 (Box 4)
        - Program Data 1981-1982 (Box 4)
        - Admissions 1982 (Box 4)
      - Performance and Research
        - Summary of Student Performance Data 1962-1967 (Box 4)
        - Student Papers (scattered) 1963-1970, 2 folders (Box 5)
        - Abstracts of Research by Clinical 1965-1975, 1980 (Box 5)
        - Nursing Specialists, 6 folders (Box 5)
        - Sigma Theta Tau 1979-1981 (Box 5)
        - Who's Who Among Students (Nominations) 1981-1982 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Financial Aid
          - General 1981-1982 (Box 5)
          - Scholarships 1981-1982 (Box 5)
          - GSTAS 1979-1982 (Box 5)
        - Form for Student Evaluation of Program 1962-1965 (Box 5)
        - Information on Professional Nurse Traineeship 1970 (Box 5)
        - Nursing Master Student Organization 1980-1982 (Box 5)
    - Alumni
      The Alumni series is noteworthy for two things: several letters in the Reunion folders describing the activities of alumni since graduating; the results of the extensive 1974 and 1976 surveys which trace the aggregate occupations, activities, and plans of alumni.
      - Reunions (including correspondence)
        - 1966 (Box 5)
        - 1969, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Survey of Graduates
        - Information on Students Who Have Graduated 1964-1974 (Box 5)
        - 1974 Letter and Survey Form (Box 5)
        - Results of 1974 Survey (Box 5)
        - 1975 Letter (Box 5)
        - 1976 Letter and Survey Form (Box 5)
        - Results of 1976 Survey (Box 5)
        - 1979 Survey Form (Box 5)
      - Research Published by Former Students 1967-1971 (Box 5)
    - Rackham
      - Administrative Council: Minutes and Related Documents
        - 1980-1981 (Box 5)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
      - Admissions 1980 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence 1981-1982 (scattered) (Box 5)
      - Doctoral Requirements 1982 (Box 5)
      - Executive Board Meeting Minutes 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - Minority Students 1981 (Box 5)
      - Residence Requirements 1981 (Box 5)
      - Transfer of Credits 1980-1981 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous 1978-1982 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Chairperson's Travelling File 1972 (Box 5)
      - Secretarial Procedures and Manuals Undated (Box 5)
      - Documents (scattered) (Box 5)
  - R. Faye McCain 1977-1979
    - Teaching
      The R. Faye McCain subseries ([1960] 1977-1979) represents all that remains of her personal files. When she stepped down from the chair of the area in 1975, she instructed her secretary to destroy most of her office records. Hence the bulk of the material in this collection relates to her activities as a member of the graduate faculty from 1977 through 1979: syllabi, lecture notes, handouts, and scattered memos and documents. Two of her articles are also included in this sub-subgroup (those articles pertaining to the Systematic Nursing Assessment will be found in the Curriculum and Program Design series of the Grad Program subgroup). The portion of the material which pertains to McCain's long work on the National League for Nursing Accreditation Board of Review is interesting as well.
      - N513: Nursing in the Health Care Delivery Systems
        - Syllabi and Handouts, Fall 1979 (Box 5)
        - Secondary Material, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - N672: Teacher Strategies in Nursing (Box 6)
        - Lecture Notes, Teaching Aids, etc., Fall 1978, 3 folders (Box 6)
        - Final Exam, Fall 1977 (Box 6)
        - Handouts undated, 3 folders (Box 6)
        - Secondary Material (Box 6)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous Handouts
        - Body Ritual Among the Nacirema 1956 (Box 6)
        - Example of Investigation of Medical-Surgical Nursing (Box 6)
        - Content: Major Body Functions of Respiration-- (Box 6)
        - Functional Alteration of Sneeze [by R. Faye McCain] 1966 (Box 6)
        - [Five on Treatment of Respiratory and Pulmonary Conditions, from University of Colorado School of Medicine] (Box 6)
        - Post-Cardiac Nursing Implications [by R. Faye McCain] 1969 (Box 6)
        - Search or Research Quest for the Elusive Principle 1964 (Box 6)
        - [Twelve on Diagnosis and Treatment of Various Diseases and Conditions, 1966] (Box 6)
    - Faculty and Professional Activities
      - Medical-Surgical Area: Faculty Memos and Documents
        - Fall 1977 (Box 6)
        - Winter 1978 (Box 6)
        - Fall 1978 (Box 6)
        - Winter 1979 (Box 6)
    - Faculty and Professional Activities
      - Medical-Surgical Graduate Program
        - Faculty Memos and Documents (Box 7)
          - Fall 1977 (Box 7)
          - Winter 1978 (Box 7)
          - Fall 1978 (Box 7)
          - Winter 1979 (Box 7)
          - Fall 1979 (Box 7)
        - Revision of Student Application Evaluation Procedure 1979 (Box 7)
      - School of Nursing and University Hospital
        - Centralized Quality Assurance Committee 1979 (Box 7)
        - Report of the First National Conference on the Classification of Nursing Diagnosis, University of St. Louis 1973 (Box 7)
        - Report of the Nursing Search and Study Committee (Box 7)
        - University of Michigan Hospital 1970 (Box 7)
        - Miscellaneous
          - 1978-1979 (Box 7)
          - Fall 1979 (Box 7)
      - National League for Nursing Accreditation Board of Review
        - Correspondence and Documents
          - 1960-1966 (Box 7)
          - 1967-1974 (Box 7)
    - Writings
      - The Principles and Objectives of Functional Analysis for Manpower Planning and Development 1970 (Box 7)
      - Educational Preparation for Nurse Practitioners and Assistants to Nurses: A Position Paper by the American Nurses Association 1965 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Papers Presented at Workshop Entitled "Towards a Differentiation of Associate and Baccalaureate Nursing Education and Practice," University of California-San Francisco 1970 (Box 7)
      - Grant Proposal for Planning Graduate Education in Public Health Nursing 1976 (Box 7)
      - Portion of a University of Michigan Report Recommending Creation of School of Allied or Health Related Professions, with Report from National Association of Sciences Board of Medicine Undated (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Program 1972-1982
    Although the undergraduate program long preceded the graduate program, the Undergrad Program subseries ([1961] 1972-1982) contains relatively little material from before 1979. The subgroup is arranged in three series: Faculty, Curriculum, and Miscellaneous. The heart of the Faculty series is the area undergrad faculty meeting minutes from 1972 to 1982. The Curriculum series is most notable for the syllabi, especially those making the development of the core course module system (Medical-Surgical Nursing II, 1961; N431, 1972, 1977, 1979-1980; N456, 1980-1981).
    - Faculty
      - Meetings: Minutes (may include related memos)
        - 1972-1973 (Box 7)
        - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
        - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
        - 1975-1976 (Box 7)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 7)
        - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
        - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 8)
        - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - Meetings with Veterans Administration Hospital: Minutes 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - Shared Teaching Group: Minutes 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - Workload
        - 1978 (Box 8)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 8)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 8)
      - Curriculum Vitaes (scattered) (Box 8)
      - Report from a Nurse at Large 1977 (Box 8)
    - Curriculum
      - Baccalaureate Program Bulletins 1978, 1981, 1982 (Box 8)
      - Curriculum Development
        - 1978-1979 (Box 8)
        - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
      - Basic Professional Program in Nursing (effective Fall 1981) (Box 8)
      - Syllabi (scattered)
        - Freshman Year
          - Chemistry 111, Fall 1980 (Box 8)
          - Anatomy 401, Fall 1980 (Box 8)
          - BioChem 210, Fall 1976 (Box 8)
        - Sophomore Year
          - Physiology 102, Fall 1980 (Box 8)
          - Microbiology 201-350, Fall 1980 (Box 8)
          - N235: Pathophysiology, Winter 1980 (Box 8)
          - N232: Life Span Development, Winter 1980 (Box 8)
          - N260: Basic Concepts of Nursing, Fall 1981 (Box 8)
        - Junior Year: N358: Adaptation of the Family 1979-1980 (Box 8)
        - Senior Year
          - N431: Nursing Intervention in the Care of the Adult [replaced by N456 in 1980-1981]
            - Syllabi and Unit Modules: 1972 (Box 8)
            - Course Description and Introductory Module (Box 8)
            - Neurological Nursing and Special Senses Module and Instructor's Guide (Box 8)
            - Gastro-intestinal, Electrolyte Therapy, and Respiratory Modules (Box 8)
            - Pulse Alterations and Blood Pressure Alterations Modules and Instructor's Guide (Box 8)
            - Renal Functions and Reproduction Alterations and Instructor's Guide (Box 8)
            - Syllabi and Unit Modules: 1977 (Box 8)
            - Syllabi and Unit Modules: 1979-1980 (Box 8)
            - Lecture Outlines and Handouts, circa 1972-1976 (scattered) (Box 9)
            - Exams 1978, 1979 (Box 9)
            - Students' Evaluations, Winter 1980 (Box 9)
            - Miscellaneous Forms (Box 9)
          - N435: Professional Leadership in Nursing 1972-1973 (Box 9)
          - N439: Management in Nursing [later N476 and N488]
            - Syllabus 1979-1980 (Box 9)
            - Exams and Keys, Winter 1980 (Box 9)
          - N456: Care of the Adult
            - Syllabus 1980-1981 (Box 9)
            - Course Pack, Fall 1980 (Box 9)
            - Lecture Outlines 1980-1981 (Box 9)
            - Exams
              - 1980-1981 (Box 9)
              - 1981-1982 (Box 9)
            - Exam Keys 1981-1982 (Box 9)
            - Sample Exam Questions (Box 9)
            - Related Material (Box 9)
          - N478 (core): Professional Nursing Issues 1980-1981 (Box 9)
          - N488 (core): Management and Leadership 1981-1982 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Medical-Surgical Nursing II (N320, N330, N340) 1961 Course Description and Unit Modules (Box 9)
        - Physical Assessment Material 1975-1977 (Box 9)
        - Study Guides (scattered) (Box 9)
        - Syllabi, Core Material, Teaching Assignments 1973 (Box 9)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Acknowledgment of N476 Clinicians 1981-1982 (Box 9)
      - Liela Post [Hospital] Policies 1976-1979 (Box 9)
      - RN Studies 1979-1980 (Box 9)
      - Student Clinical Placements 1974-1979 (Box 9)
- School of Nursing 1975-1982
  The School of Nursing subgroup ([1969] 1975-1982), along with the separately catalogued School of Nursing Records, 1891-1980, is indispensable for gaining a complete understanding of the activities and development of the Medical-Surgical Area. Not only do the minutes of several of the School's committees bear directly upon the area, but several of the School-wide reports and evaluations contain specific sections on each area which are not usually duplicated in the area files. And, of course, every area is bound by the general procedures and regulations established by the School. The School of Nursing files consist of four series: Meetings and Committees: Minutes and Documents (hereafter, Meetings); Faculty; Students; General Topical File.
  - Meetings and Committees: Minutes and Documents (Box 10)
    Of the Meetings materials, the most important are the Area Chairperson's Meetings, the Coordinators Meetings, the Executive Committee, the Faculty Meetings, the Graduate Curriculum Committee (GCC), and the Undergraduate Admissions and Scholastic Standing Committee (UASS). (Both the Executive Committee and the UASS Committee files are missing one or more entire years of minutes.) The other committees, especially the Graduate Advisory Council (GAC) and the Undergraduate Curriculum Committee (UCC), are not unimportant, but have either very little materials or very short runs in this collection. The Undergraduate Advisory Council and three standing committees--Graduate Admissions and Scholastic Standing (GASS), Bylaws, and Nominating--are not represented in this collection at all.
    - Annual Reports of Committees 1981 (Box 10)
    - Area Chairpersons Meetings
      - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 Curriculum Subcommittee (Box 10)
      - 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Coordinators Meetings (Undergraduate)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 10)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 10)
    - Educational Resources Committee 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Elections Committee 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee
      - 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - Fall 1977 (scattered) (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 (scattered) (Box 10)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 10)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Executive Committee (Augmented [on Promotion and Tenure]) 1975-1981 (Box 10)
    - Faculty Development Committee 1980-1982 (scattered) (Box 10)
    - Faculty Meetings
      - 1975-1976 (Box 10)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 10)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 10)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 10)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 10)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 10)
    - Graduate Advisory Council (GAC)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
      - Cost Study 1980 (Box 11)
    - Graduate Curriculum Committee (GCC)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 11)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 11)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 11)
      - 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
      - Bulletin Revisions 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Primary Care Program 1977-1980 (Box 11)
      - Program Evaluation 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Research Ethics Committee [renamed Human Subjects Review Committee beginning 1981-1982
      - 1975-1976 (scattered) (Box 11)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 11)
      - 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 11)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 11)
      - Chairpersons' Meetings 1980-1982 (Box 12)
      - Guidelines, Standing Rules, etc. 1974-1981 (Box 12)
      - Secondary Material (Box 12)
    - Research Review Committee 1978, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Undergraduate Admissions and Scholastic Standing Committee (Box 12)
    - (UASS)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 12)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 12)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 12)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 12)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - Undergraduate Curriculum Committee (UCC)
      - 1978-1980 (scattered) (Box 12)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
      - Mastery Skills Report 1976 (Box 12)
  - Faculty
    The Faculty subseries is generally weak and scattered, though the Doctoral and the Research Interest Surveys files are worth remarking.
    - Appeal Procedure Revision 1979 (Box 12)
    - Bulletin 1977-1978 (Box 12)
      (scattered)
    - Bylaws 1975-1982 (Box 12)
    - Doctoral Faculty
      - Memos and Documents
        - 1977-1979 (Box 12)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 12)
        - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
      - Workshops
        - 1980 (Box 12)
        - 1981 (Box 12)
    - Handbook 1976-1977 (Box 12)
    - Information Sheet 1969-1971 (scattered) (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous Memos and Documents
      - 1976-1977 (scattered) (Box 12)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 12)
      - 1979-1981 (scattered) (Box 12)
    - Research Interest File Proposal 1975 (Box 12)
    - Research Interest Survey 1978, 1979, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - Workshops 1976, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Students
    - Appeal (Review) Procedure 1975-1979 (Box 12)
    - Crisis Service (Undergraduate) 1974 (Box 12)
    - Employment (University of Michigan Hospital Nursing (Box 12)
    - Assistant Expectations) 1978-1981 (Box 12)
    - Handbook 1973-1974, 1978-1979, 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - Research by Graduates of Graduate Program (Abstracts) 1980 (Box 12)
    - Survey of Graduate Program Graduates 1980 (Box 12)
    - Symposium (Graduate Student) 1976-1981 (Box 12)
  - General Topical File
    The General Topical File subseries contains much of importance. Particularly valuable are six proposals and reports of great moment: the Grant Proposal for Doctoral Program 1974; the Program Evaluation Advisory Committee (PEAC) Reports 1975-1976; the Self-Evaluation for the National League for Nursing, 1977; the Structure (or Decision-Making) Report, 1977; the Resource Assessment Report, 1979; the Doctoral Program Review, 1981. The National League for Nursing and PEAC reports include notable sections written by or about the Medical-Surgical (and every other) Area. The National League for Nursing (NLN) report is perhaps the single most valuable document for a researcher. It includes, among much else, a general discussion of the School's undergraduate and graduate curricula, specific course descriptions, an organizational chart for and the bylaws of the School, mini-curriculum vitae for most School faculty and administrators, budget information, and admission and enrollment statistics.
    - Administrative, Miscellaneous 1978-1982 (Box 13)
    - Affirmative Action 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - Annual Reports 1979-1980, 1980-1981 and Related Memos (Box 13)
    - Budget 1975-1981 (scattered) (Box 13)
    - Bulletin 1982 (Box 13)
    - Code of Academic Conduct 1977 (Box 13)
    - Cost Study 1979 (Box 13)
    - Common Calendar 1980-1981, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - CRAS Form B 1975 (Box 13)
    - Criteria for Sabbatical Leaves (Box 13)
    - Curriculum Development (Undergraduate) (Box 13)
    - 1973-1977 (Box 13)
    - 1978-1980 (Box 13)
    - Directories, 1976-1977 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    - Doctoral Program (Box 14)
      - Grant Proposal 1974 (Box 14)
      - Projection 1979 (Box 14)
      - Documents 1980 (Box 14)
      - Review 1981 (Box 14)
    - External Evaluations
      - Consultants' Report 1979 (Box 14)
      - External Review Report 1980 (Box 14)
    - Facilities Planning 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - Graduate Area Reports 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - Lexitron 1980 (Box 14)
    - Medical Campus Library Proposal 1976 (Box 14)
    - Midwest Alliance in Nursing (MAIN) 1980 (Box 14)
    - National League for Nursing (NLN) Criteria for Accreditation (Box 14)
    - Organizational Chart (Box 14)
    - Program Evaluation Advisory Committee (PEAC) Reports (Box 14)
    - 1975-1976, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Program Evaluation Task Force 1980 (Box 14)
    - RN Studies 1979-1980 (Box 14)
    - Research Area 1978 (Box 14)
    - Research Newsletter 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - Resource Assessment Report 1979 (Box 14)
    - Self-Evaluation Report for National League for Nursing 1977, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Statement of Mission and Goals 1977-1978 (Box 14)
    - Structure (or Decision Making) Report 1977 (Box 14)
    - Study and Deanship Search Committee Program Report 1972 (Box 14)
    - Turner Memorial Clinic 1976 (Box 14)
- Faculty and Staff
  - Arleen Hegedus Files
    - Course materials
      - N456
        - Case studies 1984-1985 (Box 15)
        - Clinical II (Box 15)
        - Course requirements, syllabus and calendar (Box 15)
        - Exam 1 1985-1986 (Box 15)
        - Exams 1985 (Box 15)
        - Fluids and Electrolyte (Box 15)
        - Inflammation and Immunity (Box 15)
        - Lecture Unit 1 1985-1986 (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
        - Nutrition (Box 15)
        - Orientation 1984-1985 (Box 15)
        - Oxygenization (Box 15)
        - Perception and Regulation (Box 15)
        - Proliferation and Integrity (Box 15)
        - Self-care-exam I (Box 15)
      - N431 and N439
        - Orientation (Box 15)
      - N431, Graduate Nursing, Winter 1979 (Box 15)
      - N433, Ethical Handout (Box 15)
      - N476
        - Game 1 1982 (Box 15)
        - Game 2-HRP I-lock-ups 1981-1982 (Box 15)
        - Game 2, 1981-82 (Box 15)
        - Game Space Colon 1984 (Box 15)
        - Game 3 (Box 15)
        - General 1984 (Box 15)
        - Space Nursing, miscellaneous (Box 15)
      - N488
        - Concepts of Management and Leadership in Nursing-Winter 1982 (Box 15)
        - Winter III 1982 (Box 15)
      - N515
        - Class Sequence (Box 15)
        - General (Box 15)
        - Sample Nursing Procedures (Box 15)
        - Seminar 1984 (Box 15)
      - N730
        - Aging 1978 (Box 15)
        - Freisen Concept (Box 15)
      - Acting Chair, Medical-Surgical 1981 (Box 16)
      - Action Plan (Box 16)
      - Bylaws of School of Nursing 1985 (Box 16)
      - Classification Nursing 1985 (Box 16)
      - Conceptual Framework 1980 (Box 16)
      - Cost study 1978-1979 (Box 16)
      - Curriculum Vitae (Hegedus) (Box 16)
      - Diagnosis--Nursing (Box 16)
      - Disaster Control Program 1978 (Box 16)
      - Doctoral Program Report 1981 (Box 16)
      - External Review 1980 (Box 16)
      - "Focus on Nursing" newsletter 1983-1984 (Box 16)
      - Gaming 1982 (Box 16)
      - Gaming Workshop 1983 (Box 16)
      - GIDI 1982 (Box 16)
      - Goals (Box 16)
      - Graduate Curriculum Task Force 1982-1984 (Box 16)
      - Graduate Education (Box 16)
      - Graduate Medical-Surgical Planning 1985-1986 (Box 16)
      - Human Studies Guidelines (Box 16)
      - Independent Study Guidelines 1977 (Box 16)
      - Legal Standards for Nursing (Box 16)
      - Medical Nursing Discharge Planning 1985 (Box 16)
      - Medical Service Plan 1973-1974 (Box 16)
      - Memo of Agreement (Box 16)
      - Nursing Care (definition) 1978 (Box 16)
      - Patient Education-Resource Guide (Box 16)
      - Philosophy-UM Hospital (Box 16)
      - Power Lecture Outline (Box 16)
      - Program Review for Graduate Curriculum 1980 (Box 16)
      - Referral Process (Box 16)
      - Regents 1981 (Box 16)
      - Report to Joan Bernhardt 1982 (Box 16)
      - Research Center (Box 16)
      - Strike/UM Hospital Reorganization 1980-1981 (Box 16)
      - Teaching and Learning (Box 16)
      - Team Leading (Box 16)
      - Tenure 1981 (Box 16)
      - University Hospital 1979-1981 (Box 16)
      - Nursing Crisis 1979 (Box 16)
      - Nurses' Strike 1981 (Box 16)
      - Strike Issues 1981 (Box 16)
      - Survey 1981 (Box 16)
      - "Winning in Nursing" readings (Box 16)
      - Workload 1982-1983 (Box 16)
      - Workload Committee, Medical-Surgical 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Josephine Sana Files 1975-1982
    - Topical 1975-1982 (Box 17)
    - Decision Making Report 1977 (Box 17)
    - New Student/Faculty Recruitment (Box 17)
    - Student Surveys 1976-1982 (Box 17)